Eric Hussman

Full Stack Developer

503.819.4820 eric.hussmann@gmail.com

erichussmann.com github.com/erihus linkedin.com/in/erichussmann

I am a skilled developer and solutions engineer with a broad range of skills. Best described as a T-shaped generalist, I specialize primarily in building PHP and Javascript applications, but my varied experiences have given me the opportunity learn and utilize many different skills to bring value to organizations of all sizes. My ability to identify or develop the right technology solution for the task has been crucial to my success. I am constantly studying to learn a new language or framework, stay up-to-date on the latest tools and trends, and push my comfort zone. I love creating unique solutions and working with teams that are passionate, motivated and full of ideas.

Skills

Backend

PHP, Laravel, Wordpress, Node.js, MySQL, Linux, Apache, REST APIs, Docker (in progress), AWS (in progress), Digital Ocean

Frontend

Javascript, Angular, React, Backbone, ¡Query, HTML5, CSS3, SASS & LESS

SaaS

Zendesk, Jira, Zapier

Tooling

git, gulp, browserify, webpack, composer, npm

Testing

mocha.js, chai.js, phpunit

Experience

Vogey, Inc / Senior Solutions Architect

JUNE 2015 - PRESENT, PORTLAND, OR

I provide technology solutions and full-stack development for Vogey's diverse array of clientele and project scopes.

- Help discover client business processes and workflows
- Identify or develop technology solutions to build efficiencies
- Help grow lines of business by researching solutions for new vertical markets
- Support all servers and codebases for client technology

M Financial / Technology Solutions Consultant

JUNE 2015 - PRESENT, PORTLAND, OR

As part of Vogey, Inc.'s team embedded at M Financial, I have overseen the technical implementation of key organization-wide projects. Vogey provides website vendor

service to over 100 M Financial Member Firm organizations.

- Engineered and actively maintain a highly available cloud-based Linux hosting platform for the website program
- Developed a multi-concept, highly configurable Wordpress theme and several plugins to furnish firms with modern, unique and cost-effective websites and tools to streamline their compliance and support workflows
- Key member in the design and implementation of M's new enterprise helpdesk software (Zendesk), including development of custom workflow apps and integrations with other systems for regulatory compliance and books and records.
- Provided consultation and development for M's marketing and communications team, helping them modernize their marketing materials with web-based tools and micro-sites.

Harlo Interactive / Lead Developer

MARCH 2012 - JUNE 2015, PORTLAND, OR

- Lead developer on a wide variety of web projects, including e-commerce, front end, API and database development, and custom CMS solutions.
- Developed a proprietary CMS on Laravel 5 and Angular. Modular architecture allows fast creation of purpose-built solutions with minimal coding.
- Specialized in creating interactive applications to suit client needs.
- Provide consultation on strategy, timeline forecasting, resource management, and technical delivery.
- Managed dev team operations, including version control, code reviews, test driven development and upgrades to our technology stack and build tools.

MediaLab, Inc. / Lead Technical Support Engineer

MARCH 2008 - MAY 2012, PORTLAND, OR

- Provided high level support for issues related to Web development software.
- Required expert knowledge of HTML and CSS, as well as fluency in PHP, Wordpress, Javascript/AJAX and Photoshop.
- Integrated InfusionSoft CRM and Zendesk APIs to create revenue generating paid support levels within Zendesk.
- Developed standards-compliant, cross-browser HTML and CSS models for use by the software for web page generation.
- Responsible for updating and maintaining company Website. Implemented SEO and analytics solutions to increase site usability and improve revenue generation.
- Supported customer education with sample files, documentation and live

Featured Work

Elemental CMS

TECHNOLOGIES: LARAVEL 5, ANGULAR, PHPUNIT, SQLITE

LINKS: http://ehussmann.gitbooks.io/elemental-docs,

https://github.com/erihus/elemental

I built this platform in-house for Harlo. We needed a streamlined way to create custom CMS solutions for clients while also having a ready-made solution to shorten development timelines. Elemental is the best of both worlds.

Elemental leverages many of Laravel 5's modern PHP features, including namespaces, interfaces, service providers and facades, and the Eloquent ORM. I also developed a command line interface using Laravel's Artisan Console tool. I designed this architecture to make it easy for my development team to install Elemental as a Composer package and get up and running. All of the heavy lifting is abstracted away and developers have only to create some basic array structures to define their CMS components. They can then generate the CMS user interface with a few simple commands in the CLI.

Elemental also exposes a REST API to interact with the Angular front-end services, as well as any other third-party integrations as needed. Elemental's front-end UI wraps the Semantic UI library in custom Angular directives.

Finally, I wrote clear and concise documentation to help onboard new team members quickly.

Parkzilla

TECHNOLOGIES:, LARAVEL, PARSE, STRIPE, MOCHA.JS

LINKS: www.parkzilla.net

CODE SAMPLES/ DOCUMENTATION: AVAILABLE ON REQUEST

Founder Tim Ashman came to Harlo with unique idea to create an app that would allow users to offer their driveway or parking space for rent. The app would have iOS and Android versions, as well as a web-based profile management tool.

In order to accommodate all three platforms, I decided to create a cloud-based API using Parse.com's SaaS. I used Parse's javascript platform (based on Backbone.js) to build a booking engine and Stripe-integrated marketplace, with API endpoints and corresponding documentation. I worked closely with the mobile app developers to tailor the API to their needs.

I then built out the web application using the Laravel PHP framework that allows users to register, connect with Stripe, and set up their parking spaces for rent with custom pricing schedules.

MSites Program, M Financial

TECHNOLOGIES: WORDPRESS, DIGITAL OCEAN

LINKS: msitesprogram.com

CODE SAMPLES/ DOCUMENTATION: AVAILABLE ON REQUEST

M Financial has over 100 financial advisor Member Firms, and nearly all of them had very outdated websites in need of modernization. The trick was to find some way to create fully branded and unique websites for each firm at a fraction of the cost they would pay on the open market.

My solution was to create a multi-concept Wordpress theme that provides option controls for nearly every aspect of the design. This enables us to quickly and easily adapt each website to the firm's unique branding and vision at very low cost and quick turnaround. We manage all the websites in a Wordpress Multisite instance which allows us to keep all of them up-to-date and secure. Custom plugins I have developed allow the firms to leverage a syndicated compliance-approved content library, and streamline their requests for support and compliance reviews.

Finally, all of this is cloud-hosted on DigitalOcean, using a network of VPS servers that I stood up and configured, highly available with 99% uptime.

Education

University of California, Santa Cruz / B.A., Modern Literary Studies 2005, SANTA CRUZ, CA